{
    "id": "c71b78f97b9646c88908395362856a94",
    "title": "Types of Sentences Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "f10ad1f872af40a79a181dbd2783d20b",
            "title": "Types of Sentences Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "The girl looked at her brother and smiled.",
                    "description": "A compound sentence consists of two or more coordinate clauses. Clauses connected by and, but or or are coordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Janet went to the library to borrow some books.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has just one finite verb and one clause. Infinitives are non-finites.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The water was so cold that we could not swim in it.",
                    "description": "So…that… is a subordinating conjunction. A clause introduced by a subordinating conjunction is a subordinate clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The little girl started crying when she couldn’t find her toy.",
                    "description": "'When' is a subordinating conjunction. Clauses introduced by subordinating conjunctions are subordinate clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I live in a large city.",
                    "description": "A simple sentence has just one clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "As soon as the bell rang, the children rushed out.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We saw a film which was based on the life of Nelson Mandela.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "His crude remarks offended me.",
                    "description": "A simple sentence has just one clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Jane and Alice had their dinner and went for a walk.",
                    "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses. Two clauses connected by ‘and’ are coordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The boys and the girls were shouting loudly.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has just one clause. Therefore it is a simple sentence.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The customers were happy because they got what they wanted.",
                    "description": "Because is a subordinating conjunction. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The meeting was held in a room near the library.",
                    "description": "A simple sentence has just one clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}